http://www.lawrence.co.uk/privacy-policy-cookie-restriction-mode

We use cookies to improve our site and your shopping experience.
Find out more about the data we collect.
Close
PaintingMain MenuView All PaintingAcrylicAcrylicView All AcrylicAcrylic PaintAcrylic SetsAcrylic MarkersAcrylic InksAcrylic MediumsVarnishes for AcrylicGrounds and PrimersAcrylic PouringOilOilView All OilOil PaintAlkyd OilsOil SetsWater-Mixable OilsPaintsticksVarnishes for Oil Painting Mediums for Oil PaintingGrounds and PrimersWatercolourWatercolourView All WatercolourWatercolour PaintWatercolour SetsMediums and AccessoriesCraft PaintingCraft PaintingView All Craft PaintingBlackboard PaintGlass PaintLittle Brian Paint SticksFabric PaintingAlcohol Ink ArtKitpas Crayons & ChalkFun with KidsPigmentsPigmentsView All PigmentsAll PigmentsAccessoriesBrushesBrushesView All BrushesFor AcrylicFor OilFor WatercolourBrush SetsTravel BrushesAccessoriesLawrence Value BrushesPalettesPainting ToolsGouacheSpray PaintPrimersBooksSurfacesMain MenuView All SurfacesPaperPaperView All PaperFor AcrylicFor OilFor WatercolourFor PrintmakingFor Drawing and SketchingFor PastelsOn the RollSamples and Trial PacksIndian PaperJapanese PaperDigital PaperDecorativePaper StretchersCard MakingPaper Making EquipmentPaper PacksCanvasesCanvasesView All CanvasesStretched CanvasCanvas RollsStretchers & CrossbarsCanvas PanelsCanvas PadsAccessoriesDIY Canvas KitSketch Books, Pads & BlocksSketch Books, Pads & BlocksView All Sketch Books, Pads & BlocksPads and BlocksArtist JournalsSketch PadsLeuchtturm NotebooksLawrence Bespoke PadsArt PanelsPrintmakingMain MenuView All PrintmakingRelief PrintmakingRelief PrintmakingView All Relief PrintmakingRelief InksLino, Woodcut & Engraving ToolsCutting SurfacesSetsSundriesGel Printing PlatesRollersRollersView All RollersArtist Quality RollersStudio RollersOther RollersEtching/Intaglio PrintmakingEtching/Intaglio PrintmakingView All Etching/Intaglio PrintmakingEtching InksToolsPlatesSundriesSetsScratchboard ArtLithographyLithographyView All LithographyLithography InksCrayonsSundriesScreen PrintingScreen PrintingView All Screen PrintingScreensInksKits & SetsSqueegeesMediumsSundriesSolar PrintingPressesPressesView All PressesRelief & Etching PressesPress BlanketsDVDsBooksDigital PrintingDrawingMain MenuView All DrawingPencilsPencilsView All PencilsSketching PencilsWatercolour PencilsColoured PencilsPencil SetsPastelsPastelsView All PastelsSoft PastelOil PastelHard PastelPastel PencilsPastel SundriesPastel SetsPensPensView All PensIndividual PensPen SetsAccessoriesAccessoriesView All AccessoriesStorageFixativeTracedownMannequinsSilverpoint drawingTapeDrawing Boards & ClipsMagnifiersErasersSharpenersCharcoalGraphiteInksBooksBooksView All BooksColouring BooksDrawing BooksStudioMain MenuView All StudioStorage BoxesEaselsDrying RacksPlanchestsTransportingSafety ProductsCraft TablesLightingMagnifiersDisplayMain MenuView All DisplayPortfoliosProject BagsMountsMountsView All MountsMountboardPre-Cut MountsMountcuttersArchival Mount PanelsCutting EquipmentFoamboardFramingTapes and AdhesivesDisplayChristmasMain MenuView All ChristmasPaintingPrintmakingDrawingVouchersLuxuryOther GiftsStarter SetsStocking FillersSaleMain MenuView All SalePaintingPaintingView All PaintingAcrylicOilWatercolourCraft PaintingPigmentsBrushesAccessoriesSurfacesPrintmakingDrawingStudioDisplayBrandsMain MenuView All BrandsMarvy UchidaSpeedball Print PosseVegan Art SuppliesMain MenuView All Vegan Art SuppliesPainting SurfacesPrintmakingDrawing
Sign In / Register
Contact
Home
Privacy and Cookie Policy
Privacy and Cookie Policy
This privacy policy sets out how this website (hereafter "the Store") uses and protects any information that
you give the Store while using this website. The Store is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected.
Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then
you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. The Store may change
this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure
that you are happy with any changes.
What we collect
We may collect the following information:
name
contact information including email address
demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers
For the exhaustive list of cookies we collect see the List of cookies we collect section.
What we do with the information we gather
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service,
and in particular for the following reasons:
Internal record keeping.
We may use the information to improve our products and services.
We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we
think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes.
We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website
according to your interests.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or
disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and
secure the information we collect online.
How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive.
Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit
a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application
can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about
your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page
traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for
statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find
useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you,
other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies.
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting
to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links
to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website.
Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst
visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement.
You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate
that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes,
you may change your mind at any time by letting us know using our Contact Us information
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission
or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information
about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998.
A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please email us this
request using our Contact Us information.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete,
please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address.
We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
List of cookies we collect
The table below lists the cookies we collect and what information they store.
Cookie Name
Cookie Description
FORM_KEY
Stores randomly generated key used to prevent forged requests.
PHPSESSID
Your session ID on the server.
GUEST-VIEW
Allows guests to view and edit their orders.
PERSISTENT_SHOPPING_CART
A link to information about your cart and viewing history, if you have asked for this.
STF
Information on products you have emailed to friends.
STORE
The store view or language you have selected.
USER_ALLOWED_SAVE_COOKIE
Indicates whether a customer allowed to use cookies.
MAGE-CACHE-SESSID
Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.
MAGE-CACHE-STORAGE
Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.
MAGE-CACHE-STORAGE-SECTION-INVALIDATION
Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.
MAGE-CACHE-TIMEOUT
Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.
SECTION-DATA-IDS
Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.
PRIVATE_CONTENT_VERSION
Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.
X-MAGENTO-VARY
Facilitates caching of content on the server to make pages load faster.
MAGE-TRANSLATION-FILE-VERSION
Facilitates translation of content to other languages.
MAGE-TRANSLATION-STORAGE
Facilitates translation of content to other languages.
_gat_gtag_UA_17663527_1
Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate
_ga
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
_gid
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
cc.cookie.guest.user
Google Analytics
_pinterest_cm
Pinterest
IDE
Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user's actions after viewing or clicking on e of the advertiser's ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
: Tries to estimate the users' bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.
PREF
Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.
NID
Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user's device. The ID is used for targeted ads.
GPS
Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.
YSC
Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.
PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS WEBSITE
Privacy Policy
Last updated: [22/05/18]
T. N. Lawrence & Son Ltd (we, our or us) operates https://www.lawrence.co.uk (Site). We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and to maintaining the security of any information received from you.
This Policy (together with our Terms and Conditions and any other documents referred to therein) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.
By visiting [https://www.lawrence.co.uk] you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Policy.
Information we may collect from you
We may collect and process the following data about you:
Information you give us. You may give us information about you by filling in forms on the Site or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use the Site, create an account, subscribe to our service, search for a product, place an order on the Site, participate in discussion boards or other social media functions on the Site, enter a competition, promotion or survey and report a problem with the Site. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, financial and credit card information, personal description and photograph.
Information we collect about you.
With regard to each of your visits to the Site we may automatically collect the following information:
technical information, including the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; and
information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from the Site (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs) and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.
Information we receive from other sources. We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. In this case we will have informed you when we collected that data that it may be shared internally and combined with data collected on this Site. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.
Cookies
The Site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the Site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse the Site and also allows us to improve the Site. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.
We use the following cookies:
Strictly necessary cookies. These are cookies that are required for the operation of the Site. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of the Site, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.
Analytical/performance cookies. They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around the Site when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way the Site works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
Functionality cookies. These are used to recognise you when you return to the Site. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
Targeting cookies. These cookies record your visit to the Site, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make the Site and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.
Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.
Disabling/enabling cookies
Users of Internet Explorer 6.0 can disable or enable cookies as follows:
Choose Tools, then;
Choose Internet Options, then;
Click the Privacy Tab, then;
Click on Custom Level, then;
Click on the 'Advanced' button, then;
Check the 'override automatic cookie handing' box and select Accept, Block or Prompt for action as appropriate.
If you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of the Site.
To find out more about cookies, including how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org
Uses made of the information
We use information held about you in the following ways:
Information you give to us. We will use this information:
to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;
to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;
to provide you with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you. If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the [order form OR registration form]); alternatively contact us at artbox@lawrence.co.uk
to notify you about changes to our service;
to ensure that content from the Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
Information we collect about you. We will use this information:
to administer the Site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
to improve the Site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
as part of our efforts to keep the Site safe and secure;
to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of the Site about goods or services that may interest you or them.
Information we receive from other sources. We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).
Your Rights and Access/Corrections/Information removal
We will provide commercially reasonable assistance (including appropriate technical and organisational measures as reasonably practicable) to respond to any inquiry, communication or request from you seeking to exercise your rights under EU data protection legislation, including rights to access, correction, restriction, objection, erasure or data portability, as applicable.
If you wish to access your personal data collected or stored by us, or if your name, email, postal address, telephone number or other personal data changes, you may correct the relevant information by contacting us at artbox@lawrence.co.uk. In addition, you have the right to restrict, at any time, the processing of your personal data by contacting us at artbox@lawrence.co.uk
You have the right to be informed about personal data we have collected, request rectification or erasure of personal data, request restriction to process your data or transfer it to a third party you have appointed.
We will identify you (the requester) to avoid fraudulent requests and we will answer without undue delay, in any case not later than within one month.
Where we store your personal data
The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you or where you have chosen a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.
Your rights
You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [artbox@lawrence.co.uk].
The Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.
Children's privacy
The Site does not address anyone under the age of thirteen (Children).
We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from Children. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personally identifiable information, please contact us at [artbox@lawrence.co.uk].
If we become aware that we have collected personally identifiable information from Children without verification of parental consent, we will take steps to remove that information from our systems and servers.
Changes to our privacy policy
Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Privacy Policy.
Applicable law
If you are a consumer, please note that this Policy and its subject matter is governed by English law. You and we both agree that the courts of England and Wales will have non-exclusive jurisdiction. However, if you are a resident of Northern Ireland you may also bring proceedings in Northern Ireland and if you are resident of Scotland, you may also bring proceedings in Scotland.
If you are a business, this Policy and its subject matter and any non-contractual disputes or claims are governed by English law. We both agree to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England and Wales.
Contact
Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [artbox@lawrence.co.uk].
Sign up to our newsletter!
We'll make sure you'll be the first to hear about:
Brand new products
Promotions & Deals
News & Art competitions
Inspiring articles & reviews
